Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
♪I plant miles of peach blossoms just for her♪
أزرع أميالاً من أزهار الخوخ خصيصاً من أجلها
♪Sweet words bloom upon those branches♪
♪تزهر الكلمات العذبة على تلك الأغصان♪
♪Love runs deep, trapped in longing♪
♪الحب عميق، محاصر في الشوق♪
♪Night listens answers to longing are the most terrifying♪
♪تستمع الليل إلى إجابات الشوق، وهي الأكثر رعباً♪
♪At my fingertips, worries drift and linger♪
♪على أطراف أصابعي، تتلاشى الهموم وتستمر♪
♪Having tasted a moment of carefree joy♪
♪ بعد أن تذوقت لحظة من الفرح الخالي من الهموم ♪
♪Today, I pluck romance and moonlight♪
اليوم، أقطف الرومانسية وضوء القمر
♪And weave them all into a painting♪
♪ واجمعها كلها في لوحة ♪
=The Ultimate Vow, Unknown to You=
=العهد الأسمى، الذي تجهله=
=Episode 16=
=الحلقة 16=
Yuwen Que led his troops to massacre my entire family.
قاد يوين كيو قواته لارتكاب مذبحة بحق عائلتي بأكملها.
What's there to explain?
ما الذي يحتاج إلى شرح؟
It's not like that.
الأمر ليس كذلك.
Your mother was called a boat courtesan,
كانت والدتك تُلقب بعاهرة القوارب،
but she was actually the Emperor of Cangzhou's favored concubine.
لكنها في الواقع كانت المحظية المفضلة لإمبراطور تسانغتشو.
The prince Yuwen Que
الأمير يوين كيو
was not your mother's true enemy.
لم يكن عدو والدتك الحقيقي.
Impossible.
مستحيل.
But I clearly saw him.
لكنني رأيته بوضوح.
Back then, your mother was set up.
في ذلك الوقت، كانت والدتك قد تم تدبير الأمر لها.
That's why...
لهذا السبب...
Could it be that all these years
هل يمكن أن يكون ذلك طوال هذه السنوات
I've hated the wrong person?
هل كرهت الشخص الخطأ؟
Young Lady Shen,
الشابة شين،
what you saw was not the truth.
ما رأيته لم يكن الحقيقة.
The one who truly harmed your mother is someone else.
الشخص الذي ألحق الأذى الحقيقي بوالدتك هو شخص آخر.
So it really wasn't him?
إذن لم يكن هو حقاً؟
Then tell me,
ثم أخبرني،
who was the real culprit?
من كان الجاني الحقيقي؟
This...
هذا...
Say it.
قلها.
Young lady, the buns are ready.
يا آنسة، الكعكات جاهزة.
The buns are here.
وصلت الكعكات.
Young lady,
يا آنسة،
it's getting late.
لقد تأخر الوقت.
Let's go back.
لنعد إلى الوراء.
You go ahead.
تفضل.
I'll take a look around.
سألقي نظرة حولي.
Young lady,
يا آنسة،
I want to tell you something.
أريد أن أخبرك بشيء.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Since you've already heard it,
بما أنك قد سمعت ذلك بالفعل،
I want to tell you the truth about your origin.
أريد أن أخبرك الحقيقة عن أصلك.
(Your father is the Emperor of Cangzhou) Young lady, this letter
(والدكِ هو إمبراطور تسانغتشو) سيدتي الشابة، هذه الرسالة
was given to me by your mother before she died to pass on to you.
أعطتني إياه والدتك قبل وفاتها لأورثه لك.
So it turns out
وهكذا اتضح
I am just an abandoned child of the Emperor of Cangzhou.
أنا مجرد طفل مهجور لإمبراطور تسانغتشو.
No wonder my mother said before she died
لا عجب أن أمي قالت ذلك قبل وفاتها
not to hate.
ليس المقصود الكراهية.
Young lady,
يا آنسة،
your mother was also powerless back then.
كانت والدتك عاجزة أيضاً في ذلك الوقت.
Powerless?
عاجز؟
Then why did he abandon me and my mother
فلماذا تخلى عني وعن أمي؟
in Cangzhou?
في تسانغتشو؟
Why?
لماذا؟
Why did he let Yuwen Que's family try to exterminate us?
لماذا سمح لعائلة يوين كيو بمحاولة إبادتنا؟
Do you know
هل تعلم
why she told you not to hate?
لماذا طلبت منك ألا تكره؟
Because she knew
لأنها كانت تعلم
your father was also powerless.
كان والدك عاجزاً أيضاً.
Is it just because he's high and mighty?
هل السبب فقط أنه متكبر ومتعجرف؟
Because he's the Emperor?
لأنه الإمبراطور؟
Do you remember those people who protected you on the road?
هل تتذكر أولئك الأشخاص الذين حموك على الطريق؟
Those people were probably secret guards sent by His Majesty.
من المحتمل أن هؤلاء الأشخاص كانوا حراسًا سريين أرسلهم جلالته.
Even so,
ومع ذلك،
then why does he never appear?
فلماذا لا يظهر أبداً؟
Maybe
ربما
he's afraid you would hate him.
إنه يخشى أن تكرهه.
I think even as an Emperor,
أعتقد أنه حتى كإمبراطور،
he has attachments he cannot let go of.
لديه تعلقات لا يستطيع التخلي عنها.
(Cangzhou Prefecture)
(محافظة تسانغتشو)
(Mother.)
(الأم.)
(Should I)
(هل ينبغي عليّ)
(take this step?)
(هل يجب اتخاذ هذه الخطوة؟)
(Emperor of Cangzhou)
(إمبراطور تسانغتشو)
Qingru.
كينغرو.
Hearing Your Majesty
سماع جلالتكم
call me this is really intimate.
اتصل بي، هذا أمر حميمي للغاية.
Over the years...
على مر السنين...
Your Majesty, show restraint.
يا جلالة الملك، تحلَّ بضبط النفس.
You're not worthy to be my father.
أنت لا تستحق أن تكون والدي.
Qingru.
كينغرو.
Back then,
في ذلك الوقت،
I had no choice.
لم يكن لدي خيار آخر.
Had no choice?
لم يكن هناك خيار آخر؟
Then when my mother was being chased and killed,
ثم عندما كانت والدتي تُطارد وتُقتل،
where were you?
أين كنت؟
When we were hiding,
عندما كنا نختبئ،
where were you then?
أين كنت حينها؟
Qingru,
كينغرو،
hold on a little longer.
انتظر قليلاً.
Mother,
الأم،
I want my father.
أريد والدي.
Be good.
كن طيباً.
Hold on.
يتمسك.
(Apothecary)
(صيدلية)
Yes.
نعم.
You are the Emperor of Cangzhou.
أنت إمبراطور تسانغتشو.
How could you ruin your reputation
كيف يمكنك أن تدمر سمعتك؟
for a boat courtesan
لعاهرة على متن قارب
and her daughter?
وابنتها؟
That's not how it was.
لم يكن الأمر كذلك.
I sent people to search for you.
أرسلتُ أشخاصاً للبحث عنك.
Then why didn't you go find her yourself?
فلماذا لم تذهب أنت بنفسك للبحث عنها؟
Why did you let her bear everything alone?
لماذا تركتها تتحمل كل شيء وحدها؟
Do you know?
هل تعلم؟
When I was little,
عندما كنت صغيراً،
every time I saw other children cherished by their fathers,
في كل مرة كنت أرى فيها أطفالاً آخرين يحظون برعاية آبائهم،
I would wonder
أتساءل
why didn't my father want me?
لماذا لم يرغب والدي بي؟
Qingru.
كينغرو.
Before my mother died,
قبل وفاة والدتي،
she was still making excuses for you,
كانت لا تزال تختلق الأعذار لك،
saying you truly loved her.
قولك إنك تحبها حقاً.
But your love
لكن حبك
was watching her die with your own eyes.
كنت تشاهد موتها بأم عينيك.
As your father,
بصفتي والدك،
I am sorry to you both.
أنا آسف لكما.
One "sorry"
كلمة "آسف" واحدة
and you think it erases 18 years?
وتظن أن ذلك يمحو 18 عاماً؟
Qingru.
كينغرو.
Let me make it up to you.
دعني أعوّض لك ذلك.
From this day on,
ابتداءً من هذا اليوم،
you will be the Princess of Cangzhou.
ستكونين أميرة تسانغتشو.
I don't need it.
لست بحاجة إليه.
Qingru.
كينغرو.
You may hate me,
قد تكرهني،
but please give me one chance.
لكن أرجوكم امنحوني فرصة واحدة.
Do you know?
هل تعلم؟
I keep thinking
أظل أفكر
if back then,
إذا كان ذلك في ذلك الوقت،
you had stood up to protect us,
لقد وقفت لحمايتنا،
maybe my mother wouldn't have died.
ربما لم تكن أمي لتموت.
Maybe
ربما
I wouldn't have taken this path either.
لم أكن لأسلك هذا الطريق أيضاً.
(Mother.)
(الأم.)
(Isn't it ridiculous?)
(أليس هذا سخيفاً؟)
(The one who should have protected us most)
(الشخص الذي كان ينبغي أن يحمينا أكثر من غيره)
(became the most cowardly of all.)
(أصبح الأكثر جبناً على الإطلاق.)
(Cangzhou)
(تسانغتشو)
Young lady.
يا آنسة.
Di.
من.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
who are you really?
من أنت حقاً؟
Why do you know so much?
لماذا تعرف كل هذا؟
Young lady.
يا آنسة.
All these years, I have been acting under the Emperor's orders
طوال هذه السنوات، كنت أعمل بأوامر الإمبراطور.
to protect you and your mother.
لحمايتك أنت ووالدتك.
So these ten-plus years of affection
لذا فإن هذه السنوات العشر أو أكثر من المودة
were merely duty?
هل كانت مجرد واجب؟
No.
لا.
I never...
لم أفعل ذلك أبداً...
Cui Di.
من هو دي.
Whatever bond we had
أياً كانت الرابطة التي كانت تربطنا
ends here.
ينتهي هنا.
Young lady, listen to me.
يا آنسة، استمعي إليّ.
From this moment on,
من هذه اللحظة فصاعدًا،
we are no longer friends.
لم نعد أصدقاء.
I truly cared for you.
لقد كنت أهتم لأمرك حقاً.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Let us charge in together
هيا بنا نندفع معاً
and rescue Her Ladyship.
وإنقاذ صاحبة السمو.
No.
لا.
We won the first battle
لقد انتصرنا في المعركة الأولى
during the war with Cangzhou.
خلال الحرب مع تسانغتشو.
We must remain vigilant.
يجب أن نبقى متيقظين.
I'll go alone.
سأذهب وحدي.
(Cangzhou Prefecture)
(محافظة تسانغتشو)
Your Majesty, urgent report!
جلالتكم، تقرير عاجل!
Speak.
يتكلم.
In the battle of Mobei, our army suffered a crushing defeat.
في معركة موبي، تكبد جيشنا هزيمة ساحقة.
The Eighth Prince
الأمير الثامن
fell on the battlefield.
سقطوا في ساحة المعركة.
What?
ماذا؟
This...
هذا...
The Crown Prince of Mobei, Yuwen Que has arrived outside the city.
وصل ولي عهد موبي، يوين كيو، إلى خارج المدينة.
He requests peace talks.
يطالب بمحادثات سلام.
My son...
ابني...
Did he come alone?
هل جاء بمفرده؟
Yes.
نعم.
Open the city gates.
افتحوا أبواب المدينة.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Go summon the princess.
اذهب واستدعِ الأميرة.
Who is there?
من هناك؟
Ru, I've come to take you away.
رو، لقد جئت لآخذك بعيداً.
Yuwen Que.
يوين كيو.
You're not capable of that.
أنت غير قادر على ذلك.
You used me.
لقد استغلتني.
The arrow is poisoned.
السهم مسموم.
What a perfect trap.
يا له من فخ مثالي!
Today will be your death.
اليوم سيكون يوم موتك.
It's too dangerous.
الأمر خطير للغاية.
Go, now!
انطلق الآن!
Loose the arrows!
أطلقوا السهام!
Don't move!
لا تتحرك!
Ru.
رو.
Why did you save me?
لماذا أنقذتني؟
If I let you die so easily,
إذا تركتك تموت بهذه السهولة،
wouldn't that be letting you off?
أليس هذا بمثابة تبرئة لك؟
I haven't taken my revenge yet.
لم أنتقم بعد.
Ru!
رو!
You even kill using such despicable means.
بل إنك تقتل باستخدام هذه الوسائل الدنيئة.
Emperor of Cangzhou.
إمبراطور تسانغتشو.
I will repay tenfold
سأرد الجميل عشرة أضعاف
for today's hatred.
بسبب كراهية اليوم.
♪Counting in solitude alone♪
♪أعدّ في عزلة وحدي♪
♪Counting the cold in your eyes♪
♪أحصي البرد في عينيكِ♪
What have I done?
ماذا فعلت؟
Chase them! Don't let them escape!
طاردوهم! لا تدعوهم يهربون!
Yes!
نعم!